Douglas A. Sorge

sorge.douglas@gmail.com LinkedIn | Developer Portfolio | GitHub

(347)-589-1348

Summary: Web Developer with a focus in modern Front End technologies.

Technical Capabilities:

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, Version Control/API: Git, GitHub, POSTMAN, REST

TypeScript, Sass, JSON, NPM, CLI API's

Frameworks: React.JS, .Net

Personal Projects: Headless CMS Blog:

Weather Dashboard:

Designed, Researched and Developed a fully featured, mobile responsive blog platform using React, GROQ query language and CSS with Sanity.IO as a CMS.

Mobile Responsive weather dashboard built with React.js utilizing the CSS Modules feature, GeoLocation API and using Open Weather API as a data source.

Dependencies include React-Router, Post-CSS, React

<u>Live Site</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

Experience:

Home Depot Oct 2020 - April 2021

Share and Swiper.js | <u>Live Site</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

• Controlled Hardware Department for presentation, safety and adequate inventory. Top tier customer service.

Amazon DSP (Big Dog Delivery) - Feb 2020 - 2020

• Made over 100 stops per day. Managed inventory via proprietary software. Kept in contact with the warehouse team to correct issues.

ETRADE Financial - Jersey City, NJ - April 2018 - 2019

- Built excel sheets for the Correspondence department that tracked existing metrics and implemented year over year volume and productivity changes.
- Periodically led weekly meetings to address project progress and staff success / concerns.
- Worked across departments to gather information for use in customer correspondence.

Sal and Lloyd's Pizza Restaurant – Staten Island, NY - Oct. 2012 to 2019

- Responsible for managing the restaurant's inventory and confirming large orders with vendors.
- Managed team ensuring all operations ran efficiently and food was up to quality standards.
- Ensured Restaurant was adhering to NYC food regulations.

Education:

- Woz-U: .Net C# Full Stack Application Development Program
- **NuCamp:** Front End Development with React
- College of Staten Island: Computer Science

Soft Skills:

Experienced Team Leader Proclivity for learning new things quickly Colossal Communication Capabilities Can do attitude

References: Upon request